Android units
-------------
px (pixels) - actual pixels on the screen.
in (inches) - physical size of the screen.
mm (millimeters) - physical size of the screen.
pt (points) - 1/72 of an inch based on the physical size of the screen.
dp (density) - an abstract unit that is based on the physical density of the screen. based on the device dpi. 
sp (scale) - similar to the dp unit but it is also scaled by the user's font size preference.

---

screen resolution = x*y. number of pixels in a screen.
dip = density independent pixel. (aka dp)
dpi = dots-per-inch

--- 

when using pixels, the actual size of an element might change between devices 
note: even for devices with the same physical size! 
this depends on each device and it's screen resolution which means how many pixels it has.
so a UI element will be bigger in a device with 100px height than a device with 75px height. 

see 'devices_and_pixels.png'

e.g: 
given two devices 5in x 5in, one with resolution of 100x100 and the other with resolution of 50x50.
(tip: imagine a grid of x small squeres based on the screen resulotion)

lets say we add a button of 4px height and 8px width.    
in the 1st device it takes 4px out of the 100px height and 8px out of the 100px width 
whereas, in the 2nd device it takes 4px out of 50px and 8px height out of 50px width.
it means the button in device-1 will be double the size of device-2!

- 

to solve the issue mentioned in the previous chapter, we can use dp units.
it calculates the actual size based on the screen resolution so the UI element would look the same in all devices!

see 'devices_and_dips.png'

---

to calculate the number of pixels per device use the following formula:

[formula]
px = dp * (dpi / 160)

note: 
baseline density is 160 dpi 

---

density Buckets:
see 'density_buckets.png'

---
