voltmeter:
רב מודד (וולטמטר)

connections:
- connect the black cord to the 'com' port
- connect the red cord to the VΩmA 
  note: the 3rd port (10ADC) is ONLY for Ampere measurements.

measurements:
the voltmeter device divided into a few areas which each represents
a different measurement type.

V- // DC volt (see 'AC DC electricity')
V~ // AC volt
A- // DC Ampere 
Ω  // Ohm
🔊  // buzzer

--

use DC volt for batteries (usually used the 20v option)
note: battery AA or AAA should provide 1.5V 

--

use AC voltage for appliances based on the electricity grid 
(usually used the 600v option)

--

use A- to check ampere
note: use the 10ADC port

--

use the Buzzer to check for wire short-circuit or an electric disconnection!
it alert if the red and black cords are connected. 
tip: we can hear the buzzer If you connect them together   

to apply such test, we can use the red and black cords on both sides of a wire (or ANY other conductor) 
if it beeps - the wire is OK (it has no disconnection) 

another great use for the buzzer is to check if a switch state is OPEN or CLOSE 

-- 

use Ω to check the ohm (an electrical resistance)
the ohm law basically refers to the tendency of a component to resist an electric current to pass through it

hold:
use the 'hold' top button to stick the last measurement result on the screen 
click it again to release/ reset it